So in this notebook,
在这个 Notebook 里
we are going to get
我们将对课程使用的数据有个更好的理解
And a few quick notes are that by clicking up here on the Jupyter icon in the top left,
有几点小提示 点击这里的 Jupyter 图标
you can actually get a list of all the notebooks that will
你会看到一个文件列表 其中包括
be used throughout this lesson as well as the solutions.
本节课程用到的所有练习及其解决方案
If you choose to download them all,
如果选择下载所有文件
and keep them on your local machine,
在本地计算机上运行
you can also do things side by
你也可以参考教室 Workspace 的顺序完成对应练习
So that's also an option for you.
按自己的喜好决定如何操作
So you'll notice that,
你会注意到
here's a notebook, here's its corresponding solution,
这里有一个 Notebook 练习 这里就是其对应的解决方案
here's a notebook, here's its solution,
这里是一个 Notebook 练习 这里就是它的解决方案
notebook, solution, so on and so forth back here.
Notebook 练习、解决方案 一直是这个顺序
And then you'll also see there's solution1.py file,
然后你还会看到有一个 solution1.py 文件
and this test1.py file,
还有这个 test1.py 的文件
and these are basically used to check
这些其实是用来检查
the solutions that you have in your individual notebooks.
你在每个 Notebook 中编写的解决方案是否正确
So if we go back to "A Look at the Data" notebook,
回到 A Look at the Data 这个 Notebook
and first just read in our libraries,
首先是读入需要的库
you'll see that right here this import test1 as
你会看到 这里有一行 import test1 as t
t is basically that test1.py file that was sitting in the back.
其读入的就是 test1.py 这个文件
And then here, we're actually just reading in that dataset,
然后这里 就是在读取数据
and storing it and df,
并将其存储在 df 变量中
and once we get ahead of that data,
一旦看到数据的前几行
we know that this cell has executed,
我们就知道代码已经被成功执行了
and we can sort of keep going.
然后就可以继续
If the workspaces aren't the best place for you to run the code and follow along,
如果 Workspace 不是你运行代码的最优选择
you can do it on your local machine.
你也可以在本地计算机上运行
So here you can see the results of the data that we'll be working with.
在这里 你可以看到我们使用的数据
And the first question here says,
第一个问题是
to provide the number of rows and columns on the dataset.
给出数据的行和列
And if we run the cell,
如果我们运行这个单元格
you'll see it says, "Nice job,
你会看到结果显示 Nice job 做得很好
there are this many rows and there are this many
数据中有这些行 这些列
columns," And you'll notice that it runs this check.
可以看到这里运行了一个检测代码
So it says t.check_rows_cols,
也就是 t.check_rows_cols
and then it passes in these two variable names.
传入了这样两个变量名称
So basically this t is that file that's in the back,
这里的 t 其实就是幕后的测试文件
and there's a function in it called check_rows and cols,
里面有一个函数叫做 check_rows_cols
that's checking the number of rows and columns that are
也就是检查这里输入的行和列
provided here against what the solution thinks should be there.
跟答案中的行和列进行比较
If alternatively there was a mistake,
如果存在错误
you'll see it says "Oh,
你会看到这样的提示
that doesn't look like we were what we were
这跟预期结果不一致
And you'll see that that just was like a flip rate.
可以看到这是一个行列颠倒的结果
So here the df shape,
这里是 df.shape
the first element, or the zeroth element is the rows.
第一个元素 索引为 0 的元素是行数
And the second element,
第二个元素
that the labeled one element is the columns.
索引为 1 的元素是列数
And so, when we flip those two,
如果将行列弄反了
basically, it gives us the wrong answers.
基本上就是错误的答案
And when we check them against the solution in the check_rows_cols function,
如果我们把这一结果跟测试里的 check_rows_cols 函数做比较
it tells us in the feedback that what we got was wrong.
它会告诉我们 回答错误
Additionally, there's a dock string in each of the function solutions,
另外 在每个检查答案的函数中都有文档字符串注释
so if you run that,
如果你运行这行代码 (t.check_rows_cols?)
you can get an idea of what it wants you to provide.
会看到函数要求的输入信息
So, it says your input should be the number of
其中提到 输入应该包含行的数量
rows and that should be an int of the number of rows in your data frame,
这个参数应该是一个 int 类型的数字 表示 DataFrame 的行数
and num_cols should be an int of the number of columns in your data frame.
num_cols 应该是一个 int 类型的数字 表示 DataFrame 的列数
So each of these functions that are in
测试文件里的每个函数
this test file have a docstring that you can check the information against.
都有自己对应的文档字符串 你可以检查其信息
So, then after that,
之后的内容
you're asked to sort of do some of this yourself.
需要你自己来完成
So it says "Provide a set of columns with zero missing values," and
问题是 给出数据中所有不含缺失值的列名集合
sometimes you might just want to create a cell to work on your own.
有时你可能需要创建新的单元格 在其中编写代码
So I'm just going to insert a cell above.
我现在就在上面插入一个单元格
And if we do like df is null,
如果输入 df.isnull()
you'll see we get a whole bunch of columns, let's here.
会看到很多列
So, isnull pandas by looking at the documentation, I guessing,
我们可以查看 Pandas 的 isnull 文档
I was thinking that we could give this like the rows or the columns,
我想一下 是不是可以这样做
so maybe like axis equals one, or something.
加入 axis = 1
It's not.
不行
So, let's do.
或者 这样
Okay. Cool. So if we run np.sum,
好的 可以 如果我们运行 np.sum
you can see that there when there's no missing values that looks like this.
如果没有缺失值 就显示为 0
And when there are missing values,
如果有缺失值
then it specifies the number.
就会给出具体的数值
So if we do like equals, equals zero, cool.
如果添加 == 0
And then there is a true or false.
就可以得到很多的 True 和 False
And I'm guessing that we could do something like df.columns,
现在我直接在外面套 df.columns[]
and just poll where that's true.
就会获得所有为 True 的列名
Cool. So, if we go in,
好的 这句代码就是
we're pulling the columns where basically the sum of the null values is equal to zero.
筛选出所有空值总数为 0 的列名
And what it says,
但是这个问题的要求是
"Provide a set of the columns with zero missing values."
给出所有不含缺失值的列名集合 (set)
So, I'm just going to take this,
所以我们可以先复制这些代码
and it says to specify this as a set.
然后将其指定为一个集合
So I'm just going to go in,
就像这样
and say, set of this.
将这些代码包括在 set 的括号里
Cool. And if we get it right,
好了 如果答案是正确的
you'll see again, get rid of this box.
就会看到 (先将下面这个框关掉)
But if we get it right, you'll see it says "Nice job that looks right!"
很好 你的回答是正确的
And if we were to have gotten this wrong,
如果做错了
so let's say we just like some "thing" Yes.
比如说 我在后面加上随便一个东西 "thing"
So not only that didn't work because it broke it,
不仅不能得到正确的结果 还会报错
but I mean, we could try.
还可以这样试一下
That doesn't look like the set of no_nulls,
结果显示 看上去不是无缺失值列名集合
there should be seven columns in your list, right?
列表里应该包含 7 个列名
So if we were to go back up here, we could change it.
然后 我们就可以回去这里 进行修改
Yeah, I should work on what that says.
我们应该按照它的提示修改
But it's not a great thing but hopefully,
这个提示虽然也不完美 但你至少
it makes sense that that didn't work, right?
明白自己之前的答案是错误的
I'll go back and change that string.
然后返回去修改代码
Okay. Question Three says "Which columns have the most missing values?
好的 第三个问题问 哪一列缺失值最多?
Provide a set of the column names that
给出那些具有 75% 以上缺失值的列
So, we can use a lot of what we just did up here,
我们其实可以重新利用这里的代码
and let's just comment this out.
让我们先把这个注释掉
I'm going to take this back to zero.
然后我把这里改回 0
Actually, this is fine.
哦 这个其实没关系
And then here, we saw that this gave us something like this.
我们可以看到这里的输出
If we divide by the df.shape zero that gives us a bunch of percentages,
如果将其除以 df.shape[0] 就可以得到很多小数
we could check if that's greater than 0.75, right?
然后与 0.75 做比较
So, that gives us a true,
这样就可以得到
if there's more than 75 percent missing.
很多缺失值比例大于 0.75 的列
And then again, we could pull that from the columns, right?
接下来 我们可以从中提取 True 的列
So, this says, basically take the number of missing values,
这里的意思就是 算出所有列的缺失值
divide it by the total number of rows possible,
除以数据的总量
if that's greater than 75 percent,
如果结果大于 0.75
then give me the column name back.
就会返回列的名称
So I think this should do it.
我觉得这个答案是正确的
And I'm just going to get comment in front of this right now.
把这个注释掉
And then, it needs a set around it.
然后还需要套一个 set
Cool. The next part says provide
好的 下一题是
a pandas series of the counts for each Professional status.
给出表示每个职业人数的 Pandas Series
So, I think, if we get the professional and there's this nice thing called value_counts.
我们可以对 professional 列使用 value_counts 函数
So, this is really useful for any categorical variable.
该函数对于所有分类变量都很有用
So basically, if this column is a set of categorical variables,
基本上 如果这一列是分类变量
then running this value counts will count how many there are,
用 value_counts 就可以得到每个类别的数量
and give you back a panda series with a count for each one of them.
并且结果是一个 Pandas Series
We can run that up here really quick just so you can see what that looks like.
来运行一下
So 13,000 are professional developers, 2800 are students,
可以看到数据中 有 13000 名职业开发者、2800 名学生
so on and so forth and if we run that hopefully,
如果运行这个单元格
we see a bar chart.
应该可以看到一个柱状图
So it says, what kind of developer are you?
代表了开发者类型的分布
And then there's a bar chart.
我们来仔细看一下柱状图
And it says 70 percent are professionals,
其中显示有 70% 是在职的开发者
about 15 are students, and then this one says,
15% 是学生
a panda series of the FormalEducation status
这个问题是 给出每个 FormalEducation 类别数量的 Pandas Series
that's going to look really similar to what we just did before,
跟之前做的非常像
"FormalEducation" and then value_counts.
对 "FormalEducation" 列使用 value_counts
If we run that, you can again see we get a bar chart of this, so that looks right.
之后再运行这个单元格 就又可以看到柱状图
And the last one is for Country.
最后一个问题是针对国家的信息
So, df Country, and again,
同样地 df['Country']
can run value_counts, it's really useful,
然后是 value_counts
and it plots the top 10.
返回了排名前 10 的结果
So you can see that these are the most represented countries in the dataset.
在这里你可以看到 这是调查参与者最多的 10 个国家
And then it says, you can also continue looking through the dataset,
这里提示 你可以继续这样来探索数据
so you might look at other columns that you're interested in. Things like that.
用同样的方式来探索自己感兴趣的列